### John Ferro

5241 Morgan Ave S. Minneapolis, MN 55419 jonafi@gmail.com (516) 965-2434



#### **SUMMARY**

Web developer with 15 years experience of front-end and back-end coding. Has held a variety of roles including digital marketing producer and digital consultant. Recently completed a 6 month Full Stack web certification course through University of Minnesota. Writes clear concise code, communicates well with technical and non-technical people.

#### SKILLS

Full Stack Web developer

Core Technologies: HTML, CSS, javaScript, MySQL, PHP
New Technologies: Node, React, MongoDB, Express, BootStrap
Additional software, libraries and platforms: jQuery, Git, Photoshop

Digital Producer

*Email*: Campaign content creation, design, coding, email list management, distribution, and post-email KPI analysis *Product launch support*: Microsites, press releases, surveys, trade shows

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 2017-2021 | J&D Tech | Minneapolis, MN

# Web Developer

Completed short term front-end & back-end assignments as a freelancer. Acted as content manager, archivist, and digital consultant for a number of clients.

Project Highlight: PeterOstroushko.com

- Recovered expired domain and set up a new web site on a new hosting platform.
- Designed and built bootstrap based site for frequently updated content.
- Trained users to use third party marketing platforms for email promotions.

# 2011-2016 | MechoShade | Long Island City, NY

#### Web Lead

Under the supervision of the Marketing Director, led a team of writers and designers to create digital deliverables such as websites and mass email communications.

# Key Projects:

- Dealer Newsletter: Converted all dealer communication from faxes to email.
   Coded HTML template and by using a third party platform, collected KPI data, modified content and frequency, grew subscriber base by a factor of 3.
- Mechoshade.com overhaul: Led a design refresh and code rewrite. Converted ColdFusion elements to PHP that halved page load times. Content changes reduced bounce rate by 50%.
- Adwords launch: Created an inexpensive Google adwords campaign and adopted SEO best practices that doubled website traffic and improved the quality of lead generation.
- ERP launch: Using XML and CSS edited and branded software elements for Infor SyteLine launch. Coded extensive edits to customer portal interface, training modules, and print invoices to make a branded experience for an off-the-shelf product.
- Trade show booth update: Added QR codes to booth art that linked to product demo videos. Created a "serverless" website for the sales team access product database in convention centers with poor WiFi coverage.

### 2000-2008 | Ernst & Young | New York, NY

#### Web developer

Built and maintained digital tools site used by EY's 130,000 employees.

- Branding Zone: With a senior developer built and maintained an intranet portal for all marketing related assets using the Lotus Domino platform.
- Photo Repository: Built a searchable document database for storing and displaying high-resolution, royalty managed photographs. Used Lotus Notes based interface with heavy HTML and XML customizations.

• Email signature tool: Conceived of and coded a web based microsite to standardize email signatures. Using only an HTML form and vanilla JavaScript, users were able to create a signature attachment that adhered to the strict branding guidelines in place.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Minnesota Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Web Development September 2020